All right. Good afternoon. It is noon,
so I am going to call the May 4th public
service committee meeting to order.
Jennifer, first item on the agenda,
please.
>> Number six, ordinance, third reading,
amending section 13.20.05.
050 general prohibitions and section
13.20.070
local limits of chapter 13.20 wastewater
treatment and disposal of the code of
the city of Cheyenne, Wyoming to revise
local discharge limits and related
provisions in compliance with MPDEes
and WPDEES
permit requirements.
>> Staff report, please.
Mr. Chair, through you Matt Bulo,
Cheyenne, board of public utilities,
water recognition division manager. I
would respectfully ask for another
postponement until June 8th. The the
local limits are currently out for
public commenting period. They should
lapse on the 30th of May. Um but I feel
that June 8th would give us enough time
to EPA comments and then go back through
the city council. Be happy to answer any
questions.
>> Um any questions?
Councilwoman Alders, you have a
question?
>> No.
>> No. Councilwoman Emmens or Councilman
Labbourne, do either of you have a
questions for Mr. Bulo?
>> I do not.
>> Okay.
>> I do not either, Mr. Chairman.
>> Thank you. Um
I think you're going to get a
postponement if we stay with our
practices. You'll get a postponement
till May 14th
or May 18th, pardon me. I can't do math,
I guess.
straight to
>> um there is an amendment correct?
>> You mean to postpone?
We have to take public comment first.
Okay. Is there any So
on um item number six, ordinance on
third reading, there's been a request
from the staff to postpone.
Is there any public comment on the item?
hearing. None. Then may I have a motion?
>> I would move to uh
That's what I was asking you to
postpone.
>> Wait, we need one to approve first.
>> That's what I thought. I um would move
to approve on third and final reading.
>> Is there a second?
>> Second.
>> Second by Dr. Emmens.
>> I would amend to um postpone until May
18th.
Okay.
>> There's been a motion to postpone until
May 18th. Is there a second?
>> Second.
>> Second by Councilwoman Emmens. Any
discussion on the postponement
discussion?
Hearing none. All those in favor of
postponing for two weeks signify by
saying I.
>> I.
>> Motion is the recommendation for Monday
night will be to postpone. Thank you,
Mr. Bulo. Next item, please. by an
ordinance, third reading, amending the
official zoning map of the city of
Cheyenne, changing the zoning
classification for land located south of
I I 80 east of Southwest Drive from
County LI Light Industrial to AG
Agricultural and AR Agricultural
Residential to Li Light Industrial.
>> Mr. Lloyd, staff report, please.
>> Mr. Chair, members of the committee, my
name is Seth Lloyd. I'm with the City of
Cheyenne Planning and Development
Department. Um, this item is on third
reading. It is a zone change located
near Southwest Drive in I80. Um there
are no changes from second reading other
than the fact the future land use map
associated map amendment associated with
this project has passed and therefore
the recommendation from staff would be
to approve this zone change. I'm
available for any questions.
>> Any questions for Mr. Lloyd?
Questions?
Thank you, Mr. Lloyd. Any public comment
on item nine?
Public comment
hearing none. May I have a motion?
>> I would move to approve on third and
final reading.
>> Motion B made by Dr. Aldrich. Is there a
second?
>> Second.
>> Second by Dr. Emmens. Any discussion?
Discussion
hearing? None. All those in favor
signify by saying I.
>> I. I.
>> I.
>> Recommendation will be to approve on
third. Thank you. Next item
>> number 10. Ordinance third reading
pursuant to section 2.2.2 plan
development regulating plan or
development master plan and section
5.6.2
PUD planned unit development district of
the unified development code amending
ordinance number 4524
by modifying certain standards of the
adopted district planning unit
development PUD for sweetg grass located
southeast of the intersection of college
drive and Avenue C.
Mr. White staff report book report
please. Chair members committee Connor
White planning and development
department. Uh this item is a amendment
to the speaker SPUD make some changes to
the community park portion. Uh was
approved on second reading. Uh staff
does recommend approval. Planning
commission recommended approval. Uh
there's been no changes. I am available
for any questions.
>> Any questions for Mr. White?
Any questions?
Thank you, Mr. White. Any public
comment?
Public comment on item 10.
>> All right. May I have a motion?
>> I move.
>> Okay. M motion made by Councilwoman
Emmens. Is there a second?
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. Labbourne. Discussion
from the committee. Councilwoman
Aldridge.
>> Uh through you, Chairman Renie. Um I'm
going to be a no vote on this today. I
had an opportunity to visit with
um the head of our community recreation
and events um this weekend. The 45 acres
is a minimum amount of park um to be a
designated city park. Um there was
conversation around um having the other
part of the 66 acres um that were to be
set aside for recreation um used for a
private entity to build indoor uh space
for basketball and volleyball primarily
is my understanding. Um the city was
told that they would be able to have
time there at that facility, but the
hours would be from 3:00 to 5:00 pm
Monday through Friday. Um not really
working for us as far as students and
children and families being able to
participate. Um there was also
conversation about having the other 21
roughly acres um or 22 acres uh
separated out somewhere else in that
PUD. um that makes it a maintenance
nightmare for our city staff to have to
maintain 45 acres in one area and then
be expected to um maintain anything else
that might be substituted in a different
area.
I don't see how this benefits uh the
public in general. Um it may benefit the
developer. may benefit the entity that
owns the facility and those individuals
that are uh fortunate enough to be able
to pay uh membership or um for that use.
Um but I believe that this is uh not in
the best interest of our uh entire
community and for that reason I will be
in no vote today.
>> Any further discussion?
Discussion
hearing none. All those in favor signify
by saying I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed.
>> No.
>> Okay. The motion fails. There will be no
recommendation for Monday.
>> Item 24.
>> Number 24. Resolution amending the
future land land use map of plan
Cheyenne, changing the land use
designation from urban transitional
residential to mixeduse employment for
property generally located west of
Roundtop Road and adjacent to HappyJack
Road and amending the urban service
boundary.
>> Mr. White, staff report, please.
>> Chair, members of the committee, Conor
White Planning and Development
Department. Uh so this item before you
staff's recommendation is actually going
to be to postpone this until
September 28th. Um this item goes with
the annexation and zone change and
assigned zoning that were all postponed
at last council's meeting to the
beginning of September. This has to go
further into September because it needs
to line up with third reading of those
items. uh this item cannot be acted on
uh for approval or anything like that
until the property is annexed. The
reason for that is it's not within city
limits. It is within the county to do
any of future land use map amendments
that are within the county. We would
have to get county commissioner
concurrence. This item has only gone to
county commissioners for comment only.
Um so there was no vote taken on this
item at county commissioners. It went to
them for comment only. They made
absolutely no comments. Um it was
presented to them with what it was, but
no comments were made. Um but staff
would recommend that no action be taken
in this item just be postponed till
September 28th.
With that, I am available for any
questions. I guess I should note
planning commission did recommend
approval of this item. Staff did
recommend approval as well, but with the
other items that need to come before it,
um staff would recommend this be
postponed to September 28th.
Okay, questions for staff.
So,
knowing I have a question then. Um,
again, knowing how I voted on the other
accompanying
issues that went with the annexation.
Um, I guess I want to hear from Mr.
Brody. How do we reconcile this with
since we're only supposed to be
postponing for two weeks at a time and
then Mr. What would happen if we just
the resolution died? It would not be an
issue to bring it back in late August,
early September. Correct,
>> Mr.
>> Um, so if the application basically was
denied, um, it would have to go all the
way back through the whole process
again. Application fees be paid, legal
notice be done, have to go back to
county commissioners for comment only,
go back through planning commission. So
it would have to go through the full
process if the resolution is killed.
>> Okay. And there are application fees
that are associated with the amendment
to the land use map.
>> Mr. Chair through you. That is correct.
>> Okay. All right. Thank you,
Councilwoman Alders.
>> So I chairman Rooney 3, I just want to
make sure I understand if this is not
um extended today, it legally can't be
carried out. But if it is it fails to be
postponed today, then all of the other
actions we've done up until this point
associated with this piece of land would
also fail.
>> Mr. Do
>> um No. So this is tied to the other
projects. Um it would change staff's
recommendation when it comes to the zone
change portion to business park. It
would not change staff's recommendation
on the annexation. um most of the land
is within the future or the urban
service boundary. Um so it wouldn't
basically nullify any of the other
projects. It would change staff's
recommendation on the zone changed to be
a recommendation of denial at that point
if this was to fail and not come back.
Um but it wouldn't just nullify or
basically change anything to do with the
other applications if it wasn't
postponed today. It would just in
September staff would have a different
recommendation if this didn't come back
uh for the zone change application
portion.
>> Uh chairman Ry through you. I just want
to ask the urban service boundary is
that that's really designated in the
plan Cheyenne BA based on 2014 or 2012
whatever that was um many years ago.
>> Mr. Chair, that is correct. So and again
with the with plan Cheyenne it's a
guiding document. It's not law. It's not
like the UDC where UDC is actual defined
regulations that everybody has to
follow. The plan Cheyenne is a guiding
document. It's supposed to help guide
our decisions, our growth, things like
that. But yes, the urban service
boundary that we currently have in plan
Cheyenne is from 2014. That may be
updated with the comp plan update that
we are going through right now. The RFP
for that comp plan update is out and
we're planning to get that started I
believe as soon as end of June,
beginning of July. Um, so that might
change with the comp plan update, but as
of right now, this basically this
application would be required. Um, but
yeah, basically everything is based off
of the 2014 version and things may have
changed. A lot of things probably have
changed is how I should put it since
2014.
One more comment. Chairman Renie through
you. I just I find it very interesting
that uh it seems to me and I could be
completely off base, but it seems to me
that we use the urban service boundary
from Plan Cheyenne when it's convenient
for us and we don't ever talk about it
when it's not. Just a just a um point of
information.
>> Mr. Chairman,
>> Councilwoman Emmens,
>> um I have a a question for staff. What
are the associated fees with this
process?
>> Mr. Mr. Chair, through you, I believe
the fee for the comp plan amendment is
around $600.
And then that generally is what we use
to cover staff time, legal notice,
things of that nature.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay. And there's no provision to keep
that credit there since this is a
decision by
council to knowing it's going to be
revisited.
>> Mr. Chair, through you unless I believe
and I can probably be corrected.
>> Yeah. I think council could do a
resolution to wave the fee because
basically fees are basically they're the
fees that we have in place are approved
by council for our applica for the
application fees. Um but again staff
>> that's true they're by ordinance aren't
they? So
>> possibly um but staff has basically the
fee that we had again that covers
basically staff's time to take it
through the process. So if it is
basically not postponed and is killed on
final reading basically for it, it will
have to go all the way through the
process again which then again goes to
planning commission, county
commissioners.
>> We have to legal notice it. We have to
basically go through the whole process
once again.
>> Understood.
All right, Mr. Leborn, do you have any
questions for our staff before we move
on?
>> No, I don't. But I see that uh Mr. Bloom
is there. I'd like to hear what he has
to say.
>> All right,
>> Director Bloom.
>> Chair, members of committee, Charles
Bloom, planning and development
director. Just want to clarify the
comprehensive plan amendment fee is
$750.
So that is the price price there. Um it
was adopted by resolution. Any waiverss
would also have to um be approved by
resolution as well.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Okay. Um,
councelor Brody, can you at least
address my concerns about postponing
till September 28th?
Mr. Chairman, John Brody, city attorney.
I think as as far as um parliamentary
procedure, I I think a motion to
recommmit or refer is your proper avenue
that allows you to have a date certain.
If it's a motion to postpone,
technically under Roberts, I think that
would require a two-eek postponement.
So, um, if the will of the body is to
delay to that date certain, a motion to
recommmit to committee is probably your
best approach. Thank you.
Okay,
that concludes staff report. I think it
already asked for public
the report from the applicant.
uh chairman, committee members, Brad
Fred, Emmens, AVA, um obviously the the
applicant would like to keep it all
together. So if it gets recommitted or
however you're going to move it, it
would be best for them all to to stay
together. So since the annexation and
zone change were moved back, we would
prefer that this move back with it. So
be happy to answer any questions.
>> Any questions for Mr. Emmens?
Thank you.
Okay. Any any public comment?
All right. We have a motion to adopt.
>> Second.
>> Oh, I'm sorry. I would move to to uh
recommmit committee until September
28th.
>> Councilman, we have to have a motion to
adopt first and then we can
>> Sorry.
>> I would move to adopt.
>> Is there a second?
>> Second.
Okay, there's a motion made and
seconded. Discussion.
Now, I would entertain a motion to
recommmit or to commit.
>> Mr. Chairman, I would uh move to
recommmit to committee until September
28th.
>> Is there a second?
>> Second.
>> Second by motion made to recommit by
Councilwoman Emmens. Mot seconded by
Councilman Lebourne. discussion on
essentially the postponement till
September 28th.
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman,
>> Councilwoman Emmens,
>> I I don't think it makes any sense to do
anything other than this in order to
keep everything together. Um, we
obviously have a lot of research to do
between now and then. Um, and I think
this makes the most sense to keep
everything connected together until we
can decide what's happening with this.
>> Okay. Thank you, Councilwoman Aldridge.
>> Uh, Chairman Renie through you. I would
agree with my colleague from W 2. Um,
however, my vote uh to to recommmit this
to September 28th should in no way be
interpreted as support of this project.
Councilman Labour, any discussion?
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. I think it's
clear that uh this difficult and
confusing
matter uh be thoroughly reviewed and
that's uh what the opportunity is going
to happen for us to do so. So, I I also
support uh this postponement.
>> Thank you, Councilman. Any further
discussion?
discussion
hearing. None. All those in favor of
recommitting until September 28th
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Uh recommendation for Monday night will
be to recommit this item to September
28th. That concludes our business. We
are adjourned.
>> Kathy, I did a lot better than you did.
>> I know
she didn't have the people here either.
Hi. I obviously am not doing well in
this podcast.
>> I'm not being very efficient and lean,
that's for sure.
>> Have a good rest of the afternoon.
>> Thank you.